Guide to the Anne Morrow Lindbergh Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Outgoing correspondence, 1920-1973; Series VI; The series is arranged chronologically.
  - 1961-1965 (Box 115, Folder 146-159)
  - 1966-1969 May (Box 116, Folder 160-166)
  - 1969 June-1971 July 15 (Box 117, Folder 167-173)
  - 1971 July 16-1973 February (Box 118, Folder 174-180)
  - 1973 March-Dec, undated (Box 119, Folder 181-185)
- Writings, 1919-1976; Series VII
  The series is comprised of research notes, outlines, drafts, and printed copies of the major portion of Lindbergh's published and unpublished writings. There are significant gaps, however, and it is not a complete collection of her notes and drafts for all of her writings.
  The series is arranged in nine sections: Books; Articles and stories; Poems; Diaries; Notebooks; Speeches; Reviews of others' work and prefaces by Anne Morrow Lindbergh; Printed copies of Lindbergh's work; and Reviews and notices of Lindbergh's work. With two exceptions, the sections are arranged alphabetically by title. Diaries is organized chronologically by form, e.g. holograph original, typed copy, etc.; Printed copies of Lindbergh's work is arranged chronologically to illustrate the progression of her work.
  - Books
    - Bring Me a Unicorn
      - Typed and holograph drafts of Introduction (Box 120, Folder 1)
      - Typed carbon draft (Box 120, Folder 2-5)
      - Typed condensation (Box 120, Folder 6)
      - Penciled notes (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - Published diaries, 1970-1972, undated (Box 120, Folder 8-10A)
      Notes by Charles Augustus Lindbergh regarding his work on preparation of manuscript
    - Dearly Beloved
      - Chapters I-XVI (Box 121, Folder 11-17)
        Holograph draft
      - Typed carbon draft (Box 121, Folder 18-19)
      - Chapters I-V, VII, XIV-XVI (Box 122, Folder 20)
        Typed carbon draft
      - Chapters I-VI (Box 122, Folder 21)
      - Chapters VII-XVI (Box 122, Folder 22)
      - Chapters X, XI, XIII-XVI (Box 122, Folder 23)
      - Chapters I, III-VII (Box 122, Folder 24)
      - Chapters I-XII (Box 122, Folder 25)
      - Chapters II, VII, X-XII (Box 122, Folder 26)
      - Chapters VI-XI, XIV (Box 122, Folder 27)
      - Chapters XII-XIV, XVI (Box 122, Folder 28)
      - Chapters VIII-XIII, XV, XVI (Box 122, Folder 29)
      - Chapters I-VII (Box 123, Folder 30)
      - Chapters I-X (Box 123, Folder 31)
      - Chapters XI-XVI (Box 123, Folder 32)
      - Notes by Charles A. Lindbergh regarding his work on preparation of manuscript, 1961 (Box 123, Folder 33)
      - List of copies sent by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1962 (Box 123, Folder 34)
    - Earth Shine
      - Notes by Charles A. Lindbergh regarding his work on preparation of manuscript, 1969 (Box 123, Folder 35)
      - List of copies sent to Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1969 (Box 123, Folder 36)
    - Gift from the Sea
      - Typed drafts (Box 123, Folder 37)
      - Notes by Charles A. Lindbergh regarding television adaptation, 1959 (Box 123, Folder 38)
      - List of copies sent by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1955 (Box 123, Folder 39)
    - Listen! The Wind
      - Holograph draft (Box 123, Folder 40-44)
      - Holograph draft (Box 124, Folder 45-49)
      - Foreword by Charles A. Lindbergh (Box 124, Folder 50)
      - Appendix by Charles A. Lindbergh (Box 124, Folder 51)
      - Chapters I-XXXIII (Box 124, Folder 52-54)
        First typed draft with corrections
      - Chapters I-VIII (Box 124, Folder 55)
        Second typed draft
      - Chapters IX-XXVII, Appendix (Box 125, Folder 56-58)
      - Chapters I-XXVIII, Appendix (Box 125, Folder 59-62)
        Second typed draft (carbon)
      - Chapters I-XIX (Box 125, Folder 63-64)
        Third typed draft
      - Chapters XX-XXVIII, Appendix (Box 126, Folder 65-66)
      - Chapters I-XXV, Appendix (Box 126, Folder 67-69)
        Third typed draft (carbon)
      - Galley proofs (Box 126, Folder 70)
      - Book cover sketches (Box 126, Folder 71)
      - Preface to French edition by Antoine de St. Exupéry (Box 126, Folder 72)
      - List of copies sent by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 73)
      - Maps of North Atlantic flight (Box 126, Folder 74)
      - Original radio notes New York to New York flight (Box 127, Folder 75-77)
      - Radio logs, 1933 (Box 127, Folder 78)
      - Notes exchanged between Anne Morrow Lindbergh and Charles Augustus Lindbergh during 1933 survey flights (Box 127, Folder 79)
      - Clearance papers for entry into Dominican Republic (Box 127, Folder 80)
      - Anne Morrow Lindbergh's and Charles Augustus Lindbergh's radio licenses (Box 127, Folder 81)
      - Pan American Airways system radio report on Lindbergh flight, 1933 (Box 127, Folder 82)
    - North to the Orient
      - Research notes, 1935 (Box 127, Folder 83)
      - List of copies sent by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1935-1936 (Box 127, Folder 84)
    - The Steep Ascent, 1944 (Box 127, Folder 85)
      List of copies sent by Anne Morrow Lindbergh
    - The Unicorn and Other Poems
      - Typed carbon draft (Box 127, Folder 86-87)
      - List of copies sent by Anne Morrow Lindbergh (Box 127, Folder 88)
    - The Wave of the Future
      - Typed draft (Box 128, Folder 89)
      - Galley proofs (Box 128, Folder 90)
      - List of copies sent by Anne Morrow Lindbergh (Box 128, Folder 91)
    - "Reaffirmation" (reply to Wave of the Future critics)
      - Holograph drafts (Box 128, Folder 92)
      - Holograph drafts and notes (Box 128, Folder 93)
      - Typed drafts (Box 128, Folder 94-96)
    - Outlines and notes for unpublished books
      - Notes and outlines of a projected biography of Elisabeth Reeve (Morrow) Morgan (Box 128, Folder 97)
      - Mosaics from Europe
        - "England--the Enemy is Poverty," drafts (Box 128, Folder 98)
        - "Germany--Let Us Work" (Box 128, Folder 99)
        - "Memories of Falaise" (Box 128, Folder 100)
        - "Paris Left Bank," drafts (Box 129, Folder 101)
        - "We'll Get Through it Again" (Box 129, Folder 102)
      - Houses on Sand
        - Holograph drafts and notes (Box 129, Folder 103-104)
        - Typed chapter drafts (Box 129, Folder 105-107)
      - Oh! To Whom? An Anthology of Prose and Verse
        - Preface (Box 129, Folder 108)
        - Typed draft (Box 129, Folder 109-110)
        - Typed draft (Box 130, Folder 111-116)
      - The Outer World
        - First draft (Box 131, Folder 117)
        - Second draft (Box 131, Folder 118)
        - Typed drafts
          - "Adoration," "Alone at an Inn," "An Evening with Artists," "Angel of Despair," "The Apple of Happiness" (Box 131, Folder 119)
          - "Artists and Communication," "Artists and Marriage," "Artists and the World," "Autumn Thoughts," "Avec tendresse" (Box 131, Folder 120)
          - "The Bach Concert," "The Beach," "Become What Thou Art," "Before Shaw," "Behind Giving" (Box 131, Folder 121)
          - "Better than Love," "The Birthday of My Life," "Break Up a Crystal," "The Bright and the Dark" (Box 131, Folder 122)
          - "The Chasm," "Child-birth Vision," The Closing of the Wound," "Come Sleep," "Communication" (Box 131, Folder 123)
          - "Connections," "Conversation in a Car," "Cup of Tea" (Box 131, Folder 124)
          - "Despair," "Different Aspects of the World," "Difficult-to-Love Places" (Box 131, Folder 125)
          - "Europeans vs. Americans," "Fall Thoughts," "False Hopes," "First Snow," "Flax into Gold-Marriage" (Box 131, Folder 126)
          - "For Mother with Love," "Foresight" (Box 131, Folder 127)
          - "Gardners' Songs," "Gesture of Acceptance," "The Gift of Screws," "Goodbye" (Box 131, Folder 128)
          - "Happiness Can Be Given," "Have You No Pride?" "The Heart of a Child," "Hidden Hurt," "Hidden Valley of Repose," "Humor" (Box 131, Folder 129)
          - "In Grace," "In Touch," "Inner Atmosphere," "Inner Care" (Box 131, Folder 130)
          - "The Jewel in the Hand," "Joy," "Knife," "Labor of Love," "Les Dégoûts Même," "Letter from a Friend" (Box 131, Folder 131)
          - "The Lighter Happiness," "Love," "Love-as-the-Answer," "The Mask," "Medusa's Head" (Box 131, Folder 132)
          - "Message of the Sassetta," "The Mirror Principle," "Monarchs," "Monday after Easter," "Morning is Forgiveness," "Mountain Wisdom" (Box 131, Folder 133)
          - "Mountains and the Sea," "Music," "The 'New Boy' Feeling," "No Regret for Summer's End," "O to Whom" (Box 131, Folder 134)
          - "Of Giving," "Of Gratitude," "Of Prayer," "On Reading Tawney on What England Fights For" (Box 131, Folder 135)
          - "Of Taking Life," "Of Touch," "Of Understanding," "Of Vulnerability," "Of Writers," "Of Writing" (Box 131, Folder 136)
          - "Only by Embracing Life," "Only My Own Devil," "Only the Strong Can Love" (Box 131, Folder 137)
          - "Pain and Illumination," "Parents and Children," "Planes Overhead," "The Poor Connection," "Position" (Box 131, Folder 138)
          - "Possession," "Prayer," "Publicity," "Pure Retreat" (Box 131, Folder 139)
          - "Reading the Reviews," "Recollection," "Revelations," "Rooted in Imperfection" (Box 131, Folder 140)
          - "The Second Meeting," "Security," "The Seeds of Writing," "Separation," "A Sign," "The Single Flower" (Box 132, Folder 141)
          - "Sit Down," "So Sorry," "Steps in Growth," "Still as the Hub of a Wheel," "The Stranger," "The Stream" (Box 132, Folder 142)
          - "Subjectives and Objective," "Suffering is Secret" (Box 132, Folder 143)
          - "Temptations," "The Third Person," "To Be Loved is to be Invisible," "To Love One Another" (Box 132, Folder 144)
          - "Translation," "The Tulips," "Veiled Brightness" (Box 132, Folder 145)
          - "Walking by the Sea," "War," "The 'We Few' Feeling," "We Move in Infinite Space" (Box 132, Folder 146)
          - "What Flower is This?" "Who are My Brethren?" "The Widow," "Winter Tree," Winter Wheat" (Box 132, Folder 147)
          - "Woman and Artist," "Women," "Words," "Work is Love Made Visible" (Box 132, Folder 148)
          - Untitled (Box 132, Folder 149)
      - Notes (Box 132, Folder 150-151)
  - Articles and stories
    - "Air-liner to Europe: Notes from a Passenger's Diary"
      - Typed drafts (Box 133, Folder 152)
      - Notes (Box 133, Folder 153)
    - "Anywhere in Europe" (Box 133, Folder 154)
      Holograph and typed drafts with notes
    - "As I See Our First Lady"
      - Drafts one and two (Box 133, Folder 155)
      - Draft two with inserts (Box 133, Folder 156)
      - Draft three (Box 133, Folder 157)
      - Draft four (Box 133, Folder 158)
      - Research material (Box 133, Folder 159)
    - "Feeding Europe"
      - Holograph drafts and notes (Box 134, Folder 160-161)
      - Typed drafts (Box 134, Folder 162)
      - Final drafts (Box 134, Folder 163)
      - Excerpts to newsreel read by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, NBC Studios, New York, 1940 December 27 (Box 134, Folder 164)
    - "The Flame of Europe"
      - Holograph drafts and notes (Box 134, Folder 165)
      - Final draft (Box 134, Folder 166)
      - Notes (Box 134, Folder 167-170)
    - "Flying Around the North Atlantic" (Box 134, Folder 171)
    - "The Heron and the Astronaut"
      - Typed draft (Box 134, Folder 172)
      - Notes by Charles Augustus Lindbergh regarding his work on preparation of manuscript, 1969 (Box 134, Folder 173)
    - "Immersion in Life" (A Leaven of Wilderness)
      - First draft, holograph (Box 134, Folder 174)
      - First draft, typed (Box 134, Folder 175)
    - "Immersion in Life" (Journey to East Africa)
      - Second draft (Box 135, Folder 176)
      - Third draft (Box 135, Folder 177)
      - Fourth draft (Box 135, Folder 178)
      - Fourth draft with correspondence (Box 135, Folder 179)
    - "It Begins with Charity" (Box 135, Folder 180)
      Drafts and notes
    - "The Mother and the Child" (Box 135, Folder 181)
    - "My Most Unforgettable Character" (Edward Sheldon)
      - Holograph draft and notes (Box 135, Folder 182)
      - Typed draft (Box 135, Folder 183)
    - "One Starts at Zero" (Box 135, Folder 184)
      Typed draft and notes
    - "Our Lady of Risk"
      - First draft and notes (Box 135, Folder 185)
      - Typed drafts with notes and correspondence (Box 135, Folder 186)
      - Corrected draft (Box 135, Folder 187)
    - "Prayer for Peace"
      - Holograph drafts (Box 135, Folder 188-189)
      - Holograph drafts (Box 136, Folder 190)
      - Typed drafts (Box 136, Folder 191-192)
    - "The Quality of Mercy"
      - Holograph drafts and notes (Box 136, Folder 193)
      - Typed drafts (Box 136, Folder 194)
    - Unpublished drafts, outlines, and notes for stories
      - "Another Apple"
        - Holograph draft (Box 136, Folder 195-196)
        - Typed draft (Box 136, Folder 197-198)
      - "Goodbye," "The Green Sofa Sunday School" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 199)
      - "Just Another Fairy Tale" (holograph booklet) (Box 137, Folder 200)
      - "The Music Lesson" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 201)
      - "My Little Love" (holograph draft) (Box 137, Folder 202)
      - "The Pool," "The Piazza Theatre," "Reading" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 203)
      - "Visibility Zero"
        - Holograph draft and notes (Box 137, Folder 204)
        - Typed drafts (Box 137, Folder 205)
      - "What! You Here?" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 206)
      - "The Artistic Approach" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 207)
      - "Betsey Barton" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 208)
      - "For Better or For Worse" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 209)
      - "The Journey of the Magi" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 210)
      - "The Roller Coaster" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 211)
      - "Snail-Shell," "The Tulips" (drafts) (Box 137, Folder 212)
      - Notes for possible stories, articles, and themes (Box 137, Folder 213-214)
  - Poems
    - "Across the Hudson," "All Saint's Day," "Alms," "Autumn, 1939," "Back to the Island," "Bare Tree," "Birthday Song for Mother- 1921," "Broken Shell," "Burning Tree" (Box 137, Folder 215)
    - "Caprice," "A Certain Woman," "Closing In," "The Deep Well" (Box 137, Folder 216)
    - "Dogwood," "Elegy Under the Stars," "Even ---," "Family Album" (Box 137, Folder 217)
    - "A Final Cry," "Flight of Birds," "Growing Up," "Height" (Box 137, Folder 218)
    - "Joy," "A Leaf, a Flower, and a Stone," "Letter with a Foreign Stamp," "The Lights of Man," "The Little Mermaid," "Magnolia Tree at Night" (Box 137, Folder 219)
    - "The Man and the Child," "Mid-Summer," "Mountain," "Murmurings of the Unmathematical Mind," "New England" (Box 138, Folder 220)
    - "No Harvest Ripening," "No Twilight," "November Wind" (Box 138, Folder 221)
    - "Pilgrim," "Prayer," "Presence," "Presentment," "Promethea" (Box 138, Folder 222)
    - "Remembrance," "Revisitation," "A Road of Night" (Box 138, Folder 223)
    - "Safe," "Saint for Our Time," "Scattered Broken Clouds," "Sea Shell or Star," "Seasons," "Second Swing," "Security" (Box 138, Folder 224)
    - "Skiers World," "Sky Poem," "Song of the Timid Tens," "Space," "The Stone," "The Stream" (Box 138, Folder 225)
    - "Success," "Summer Rain," "Swallows," " Testament," "To ---," "To a Young Boy Singing," "To an Idealist" (Box 138, Folder 226)
    - "The Trolls," "Two Citadels," "Unicorn," "Unicorn in Captivity," "Unknown Penitent" (Box 138, Folder 227)
    - "Visitation," "Where?" "Winter Tree," "Within the Wave" (Box 138, Folder 228)
    - Untitled drafts and notes (Box 138, Folder 229-232)
  - Diaries
    - Holograph originals
      - 1929-1933 September 24 (Box 138, Folder 233-237)
      - 1933 September 25-1933 December 19 (Box 139, Folder 238-240)
      - 1939 February 18-1940 August 24 (Box 140, Folder 241-244)
      - 1943 April 14-1948 November (Box 141, Folder 245-248)
      - 1948 November 9-1951 August 2 (Box 142, Folder 249-252)
      - 1952-1956 August (Box 143, Folder 253-256)
      - 1959 December 8-1961 January 19 (Box 144, Folder 257-258)
    - Holograph carbons
      - 1939 September 4-1941 June 22 (Box 144, Folder 259-265)
      - 1941 June 22-1948 November (Box 145, Folder 266-272)
      - 1948 November 9-1954 September 10 (Box 146, Folder 273-279)
      - 1955 October 15-1959 January 12 (Box 147, Folder 280-286)
      - 1959 January 14-1962 June (Box 148, Folder 287-294)
      - 1963 April 15-1970 October 4 (Box 149, Folder 295-303)
      - 1971 January 22- 1973 August 2 (Box 150, Folder 304-307)
    - Typescripts
      - 1919-1926 September 22 (Box 150, Folder 308-318)
      - 1927 July 12-1933 July 8 (Box 151, Folder 319-322)
      - 1933 July 9-1933 July 25
        - Copies 1-4 (Box 151, Folder 323-326)
        - Corrected copy (Box 151, Folder 327)
      - 1933 July 26-1933 August 16
        - Copies 1-3 (Box 151, Folder 328-330)
        - Corrected copy (Box 152, Folder 331)
      - 1933 August 17-1933 September 2
        - Copies 1-4 (Box 152, Folder 332-335)
        - Corrected copy (Box 152, Folder 336)
      - 1933 September 3-1933 September 25
        - Copies 1-4 (Box 152, Folder 337-340)
        - Corrected copy (Box 152, Folder 341)
      - 1933 September 25-1933 October 22
        - Copies 1-4 (Box 152, Folder 342-345)
        - Corrected copy (Box 152, Folder 346)
      - 1933 October 23-1933 November 30
        - Copies 1-4 (Box 152, Folder 347-350)
        - Corrected copy (Box 152, Folder 351)
      - 1933 December 1-1933 December 19
        - Copy 1 (Box 152, Folder 352)
        - Copies 2-4 (Box 153, Folder 353-355)
        - Corrected copy (Box 153, Folder 356)
      - 1934 August 1-1938 February 16 (Box 153, Folder 357-363)
      - 1938 February 17-1939 June 19 (Box 154, Folder 364-372)
      - 1939 June 20-1942 December 6 (Box 155, Folder 373-381)
      - 1942 December 7-1944 October (Box 156, Folder 382-386)
      - 1944 October 27-1946 October 22
        - Copy 1 (Box 156, Folder 387)
        - Copy 2 (Box 156, Folder 388)
      - 1947 January 5-1947 July 31
        - Copy 1 (Box 156, Folder 389)
        - Copy 2 (Box 156, Folder 390)
      - 1947 August 1-1947 August 13 (Box 156, Folder 391)
    - Diary excerpts
      - Typed drafts
        - 1959 January 19-1960 October 26 (Box 157, Folder 392)
        - 1959 January 19-1960 November 13 (Box 157, Folder 393-395)
          Copies 1-3
        - 1960 November 14-1961 May 8 (Box 157, Folder 396)
      - Holograph drafts, 1961 August 17-1971 November (Box 157, Folder 397)
      - Typed drafts, 1961 August 31-1961 September 28 (Box 157, Folder 398)
      - Holograph drafts, 1961 December-1962 May (Box 157, Folder 399)
      - Typed drafts
        - 1961 September 28-1961 November 18 (Box 157, Folder 400)
        - 1961 October 7-1962 September 6 (Box 157, Folder 401-406)
      - Holograph drafts, 1962 September 1-1962 September 6 (Box 158, Folder 407)
      - Typed drafts, 1962 October 10-1962 December 6 (Box 158, Folder 408)
      - Holograph drafts, 1962 October 12-1963 October 12 (Box 158, Folder 409-411)
      - Typed drafts
        - 1963 January 26-1963 September 20 (Box 158, Folder 412-414)
        - 1963 October 8-1967 February (Box 159, Folder 415-419)
  - Notebooks
    - Notebook, Christmas, 1922 (Box 159, Folder 420)
    - Flowered yellow notebook (carbon typescript), 1934-1940 (Box 159, Folder 421)
    - "Little red book" (holograph, bound), 1940-1942 (Box 159, Folder 422)
    - "Little red book" (typescript), 1940-1942 (Box 159, Folder 423)
    - "Little blue book" (holograph bound), 1944-1947 (Box 159, Folder 424)
    - "Little blue book" (typescript), 1944-1947 (Box 159, Folder 425)
    - Notebook (holograph, bound), 1948, undated (Box 159, Folder 426)
  - Speeches
    - American First and non-intervention speech drafts (Box 160, Folder 427)
    - Acceptance speeches for award of medals by Anne Morrow Lindbergh and Charles A. Lindbergh at the National Institute of Social Sciences, 1968 November 21 (Box 160, Folder 428)
      Penciled, typed, and xeroxed drafts
    - Dedication of Chilton House, 1972 October 17 (Box 160, Folder 429)
      Typed draft
    - "Earth values," address given at John M. Greene Hall at Smith College, 1970 (Box 160, Folder 430)
      Typed and xeroxed drafts
    - "Feeding Europe" (radio address), 1940 December 24 (Box 160, Folder 431)
    - "Introduction of Miss Rumer Godden," given at Cosmpolitan Club, Undated (Box 160, Folder 432)
      Penciled and typed drafts
    - "Introduction of Nancy Wilson Ross", 1968 (Box 160, Folder 433)
    - Relief in Europe; "The Wind of Privation or the Sun of Mercy"
      See: "Feeding Europe", box 160, folder 431
    - Speech regarding French relief, [1947?] (Box 160, Folder 434)
  - Reviews of others' work and prefaces written by Anne Morrow Lindbergh
    - Grey Eminence by Aldous Huxley, a review "Religion and Politics" by Anne Morrow Lindbergh
      - Penciled and typed drafts (Box 161, Folder 435-436)
      - Typed drafts (Box 161, Folder 437)
    - Of Images and Shadows by Iris Origo, a review by Anne Morrow Lindbergh (Box 161, Folder 438)
      Penciled draft
    - While We Are Absent by Ann Leighton, a review by Anne Morrow Lindbergh
      - Penciled drafts (Box 161, Folder 439)
      - Typed drafts (Box 161, Folder 440)
    - Spring Returns by Haniel Long, preface by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1958 (Box 161, Folder 441)
    - Wind, Sand and Stars by Antoine de St. Exupéry, a review "Adventurous Writing" by Anne Morrow Lindbergh (Box 161, Folder 442)
    - Wind, Sand and Stars and other books by Antoine de St. Exupéry, a review "Bread, That Is Not Stone" by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1939 (Box 161, Folder 443)
  - Printed copies of Anne Morrow Lindbergh's work
    - "A Village in the Bahamas" (article) The Wheel, 1920 November (Box 161, Folder 444)
    - "Rachmaninoff" (review) The Wheel, 1921 February (Box 161, Folder 444)
    - "Tomorrow Will Be Monday" (article) The Wheel, 1922 March (Box 161, Folder 444)
    - "Drawbacks" (article) The Wheel, 1922 May (Box 161, Folder 444)
    - "English Hills" (poem) The Wheel, 1922 December (Box 161, Folder 445)
    - "Latin" (article) The Wheel, 1923 March (Box 161, Folder 445)
    - "Ambition, Distraction, Uglification and Derision" (article) The Wheel, 1923 May (Box 161, Folder 445)
    - "Ships," "Paderewski," "Irish Fairy Tales" (poems and review) The Wheel, 1923 December (Box 161, Folder 446)
    - "Distance Lends Enchantment" The Wheel, 1924 March (Box 161, Folder 446)
    - "April," "Studying a Recipe" (poems) The Wheel, 1924 June (Box 161, Folder 447)
    - "A Certain Woman," "Letter with a Foreign Stamp" (poems) Smith College Monthly, 1927 February (Box 162, Folder 448)
    - "Grand Opera" (article) Smith College Monthly, 1927 April (Box 162, Folder 449)
    - "Lida Was Beautiful" (story) The New Student, 1928 October (Box 162, Folder 450)
    - "Primroses" (story) Smith College Monthly, [1924-1928] (Box 162, Folder 451)
    - "Flying Around the North Atlantic" (article) National Geographic Magazine, 1934 September (Box 162, Folder 452)
    - North to the Orient, 1935 (Box 162, Folder 453)
    - North to the Orient, (book condensation) Reader's Digest, 1937 April (Box 162, Folder 454)
    - Listen! The Wind, 1938 (Box 162, Folder 455)
    - Listen! The Wind (book condensation) Reader's Digest, 1939 April (Box 163, Folder 456)
    - Wind, Sand, and Stars by Antoine de St. Exupéry, (review) The Saturday Review, 1939 October 14 (Box 163, Folder 457)
    - The Wave of the Future (essay), 1940 (Box 163, Folder 458)
    - "Prayer for Peace," (article) Reader's Digest, 1940 January (Box 163, Folder 459)
    - "Visitation," "Elegy under the Stars," "Aims" (poems) Atlantic Monthly, 1941 April (Box 163, Folder 460)
    - "Testament," "A Final Cry" (poems) Atlantic Monthly, 1941 April (Box 163, Folder 461)
    - "Reaffirmation" (article) Atlantic Monthly, 1941 June (Box 163, Folder 462)
    - Grey Eminence by Aldous Huxley, (review) Common Sense, 1942 June (Box 163, Folder 463)